Gerard P. Kuiper papers 1894-1992 (bulk 1949-1973)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series X: Research, 1894-1973:
  - Subseries 12: Other Site Surveys, 1964-1973
    - Tumamoc Hill, 1962; 1971, (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - White Mountain, California reports, 1950; 1970-1973 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Aerial charts, undated (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 13: Observations, 1921- 1970
    - Sub-subseries 1: General
      - Asteroids Studies I. Photometrics, undated (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - Enlargement of K344, K348, K349, K350, K351, K352, K359, undated (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - Eucanmia asteroid 15, 1952 (Box 51, Folder 8)
      - Herculina asteroid 532, January 2, 1954 (Box 51, Folder 9)
      - Iapetus, Titan, Hyperion, Neptune, April 19, 1953 (Box 51, Folder 10)
      - Iris asteroid 7, 1950; 1952 (Box 51, Folder 11)
      - Klotho Asteroid 97, November 4-5, 1949; 1952 (Box 51, Folder 12)
      - Laetitia Asteroid 39, 1949; 1952 (Box 51, Folder 13)
      - Metis Asteroid 9, November 2, 1949 (Box 51, Folder 14)
      - Orionis Asteroid 12, undated (Box 51, Folder 15)
      - Toutanis Asteroid 17, April 1 -2, 1953 (Box 51, Folder 16)
      - Uranus and Thetis, March 28, 1953 (Box 51, Folder 17)
      - Vesta Asteroid 4, 1952 (Box 51, Folder 18)
      - Catalina site, 1963-1964 (Box 51, Folder 19)
      - Catalina inside 61 inch dome temperature, 1968-1970 (Box 51, Folder 20)
      - Catalina outside 61 inch dome temperature, 1966-1970 (Box 51, Folder 21)
      - Hilger 10-11, 13-16, Ch4, undated (Box 51, Folder 22)
      - Infrared observations of planets and satellites, 1957 (Box 51, Folder 23)
      - Infrared observing program, 1963-1964 (Box 51, Folder 24)
      - Lick Observatory NGC2244, [1926-1946] (Box 51, Folder 25)
      - Lick Observatory NGC2353, 1933-1950 (Box 51, Folder 26)
      - Lick Observatory NGC2264, [1921-1944] (Box 51, Folder 27)
      - Lick Observatory NGC2362, 1931; 1943,; 1950 (Box 51, Folder 28)
      - Lick Observatory NGC6871, 1930-1944 (Box 51, Folder 29)
      - Lick Observatory NGC7380, [1929-1939] (Box 51, Folder 30)
      - Loose notes, undated (Box 51, Folder 31)
      - Manuscript measures for volume 165, 1922-1929 (Box 51, Folder 32)
      - Mars observations and photographs, 1956 (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Mars/Moon observations, 1962-1963 (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Mars satellites photometry, 1956 (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - McDonald Observatory, 1958-1960 (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - Mount Palomar 200 inch observation notes, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - Observing programs 82 inch telescope, [1956-1958] (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - Observing program Texas, 1952 (Box 52, Folder 7)
      - Observing schedule 61 inch telescope, 1966-1968 (Box 52, Folder 8)
      - Observing telescope schedules, 1952-1962 (Box 52, Folder 9)
      - Pbs Photometry records, 1955 (Box 52, Folder 10)
      - Pbs Photometry reduction, [1955] (Box 52, Folder 11)
      - Pluto, April 4, 1953 (Box 52, Folder 12)
      - Pluto, April 8, 1953 (Box 52, Folder 13)
      - Pluto, April 9, 1953 (Box 52, Folder 14)
      - Pluto Uranus, April 7, 1953 (Box 52, Folder 15)
      - Saturn rings observations, 1966 (Box 52, Folder 16)
      - Sensitivity test, April 20, 1953 (Box 52, Folder 17)
      - Solar Eclipse, May 9, 1929 (Box 52, Folder 18)
      - Star survey 36 inch telescope Lick Observatory, 1936 (Box 52, Folder 19)
      - Stars - Photometry with 13 inch, [1938] (Box 52, Folder 20)
      - Titan, Jupiter, Saturn, undated (Box 52, Folder 21)
      - Trojans, 1958 (Box 52, Folder 22)
      - Uranus and miscellaneous, undated (Box 52, Folder 23)
      - UV planetary spectra and IR planetary spectra, undated (Box 52, Folder 24)
      - Venus polarization, 1959 (Box 52, Folder 25)
      - Miscellaneous, [1950] (Box 52, Folder 26)
    - Sub-subseries 2: Observation Notebooks
      - 40 inch telescope; small spectrograph,D series, [1938-1940] (Box 52, Folder 27)
      - 82 inch results infrared research, [1946] (Box 52, Folder 28)
      - Catalina station site 1, weather records, 1963-1964 (Box 52, Folder 29)
      - Crossley reflector telescope slit less spectrograms, [1933-1934] (Box 52, Folder 30)
      - D series spectrograms. Yerkes Observatory, 1937-1939 (Box 52, Folder 31)
      - Double star measures I and II, 1933-1935 (Box 52, Folder 32)
      - Double star measures III and IV, 1935-1949 (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - H.R. Duplicity program, 1932-1935 (Box 53, Folder 2)
      - H.R.Double star program, undated (Box 53, Folder 3)
      - H.R. Double star survey, 1933-1937 (Box 53, Folder 4)
      - Infrared spectrometer, 1946-1956 (Box 53, Folder 5)
      - K-spectrograph McDonald observatory, 1-2, 1939-1943 (Box 53, Folder 6)
      - K-spectrograph McDonald Observatory, 3, January. 15, 1943-September. 10, 1946 (Box 53, Folder 7)
      - K-spectrograph quartz tail end,4, 1950 (Box 53, Folder 8)
      - Measures of proper motions on plates taken by Van Maamen on Mount Wilson, May 6-27, 1942 (Box 53, Folder 9)
      - Micrometer 82 inch, I and II, 1942-1950 (Box 53, Folder 10)
      - Micrometer 82 inch, III and VI, June 1956-1962 (Box 53, Folder 11)
      - Photometry, 1940-1943 (Box 53, Folder 12)
      - Reductions disk meter, etc., [1949-1954] (Box 53, Folder 13)
      - Terrestrial photography T series, 1946-1948 (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Sub-subseries 3: Observation Card catalogs
      - All known double stars brighter than 6m.51 H.S. 1, undated (Box 54, Folder 1)
      - Large Parallax stars, 1h-23h, undated (Box 54, Folder 2)
      - Double star program, 1929-1932; Photometric program (Box 54, Folder 3)
      - Cards of PM >-0.28 and greater and => to 0.050 for the whole sky. 0h – 12h, undated (Box 55, Folder 1)
      - Large Parallax stars, 1h-23h, undated (Box 55, Folder 2)
      - Double star program, 1929-1932; Photometric program (Box 55, Folder 3)
      - Cards on PM 0.28 stars; Charts 0h Om- 14h, 1932 (Box 56, Folder 1)
      - Cards on PM 0.28 stars; Charts 15h Om- 22h, undated (Box 56, Folder 2)
      - Cards on PM 0.28 stars; Charts 22h Om- 23h Cook Asteroid, undated (Box 56, Folder 3)
      - Other observations, undated (Box 56, Folder 4)
      - PM survey charts; Chart 0h 0m – 11:27, undated (Box 56, Folder 5)
- Series XI: Trip Reports., 1958-1973
  This series is arranged chronologically. The bulk of the trips are to the Soviet Union from 1958-1959, 1967-1970. These trips were taken by Dr. Kuiper and other American astronomers. There are reports of trips taken by Dr. Kuiper to Hamburg Germany 1964; Prague Czechoslovakia 1967; Hawaii 1970; Brighton, England 1970 Flagstaff, Arizona 1972; Mexico 1973.
  As well as trips to Sydney, Australia and Torun, Poland taken by Tom Gehrels for Dr. Kuiper who was ill. There are also records of Russian scientists visiting Dr. Kuiper in the United States.
  - Trip to Moscow for 10th General Assembly meeting of the IAU by Dr. Kuiper, August 1958 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Visit of Soviet Union scientists to Yerkes Observatory., December 25-27, 1959 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Trip to Hamburg Germany for IAU meetings by Gerard Kuiper, August 30-September 2, 1964 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Soviet Union astronomer's visit to the University of Arizona., November 4-6, 1964 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Trip to Prague, Czechoslovakia IAU meeting by Gerard Kuiper, August 22-31, 1967 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Trip to Prague, Czechoslovakia IAU meeting by Gerard Kuiper, August 22-31, 1967 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Trip through the Soviet Union by Tobias Owen, May 13-June 13, 1967 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Trip to Soviet Union by Dale P. Cruikshank, 1967-1969 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Trip to Hawaii by Gerard Kuiper, June 24-28, 1970 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Trip to Brighton, England, IAU 14th General Assembly meeting by Dr. Kuiper, August 17-25, 1970 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Trip to the Soviet Union by Dale P. Cruikshank, August 17-25, 1970 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Trip to Lowell Observatory, Flagstaff by Gerard Kuiper, August 17-25, 1970 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Trip to the Soviet Union by William B. Hubbard, January 1- August 15,1973 (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Trip report by Tom Gehrels IAU meetings in Sydney Australia, Torun Poland, etc., July 23-September 14, 1973. (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - Trip to Mexico by Gerard Kuiper, October 18-27, 1973 (Box 57, Folder 14)
- Series XII: World War II, 1938-1951.
  This series is arranged chronologically. The series documents Dr. Kuiper’s activities during World War II as a member of the ALSOS Mission. It contains reports, interviews, correspondence, articles and also an account of military, naval and air operations in the Netherlands.
  The ALSOS Mission was part of the Manhattan Project, an effort during World War II by Great Britain and the United States to create an atomic bomb. The ALSOS Mission followed the Allied invasion of Italy in September 1943, to investigate the German nuclear energy project. The ALSOS Mission personnel followed close behind the front lines, and occasionally behind enemy lines, first in Italy, and later in France and Germany. ALSOS personnel managed to find and remove many of the German research effort's personnel, along with a substantial portion of the surviving records and equipment.
  - ALSOS Mission (1), 1945 (Box 57, Folder 15)
  - ALSOS Mission (2), 1945 (Box 57, Folder 16)
  - ALSOS Mission (3), 1945 (Box 57, Folder 17)
  - ALSOS reunions, 1958-1970 (Box 57, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1938-1951 (Box 57, Folder 19)
  - Fate of some German Observatories. Schauinsland Observatory, 1941-1946 (Box 57, Folder 20)
  - German Astronomy during World War II, 1941-1946 (Box 57, Folder 21)
  - German Ionospheric and prediction service papers, 1938-1945 (Box 57, Folder 22)
  - The Invasion of Holland, 1943-1945 (Box 57, Folder 23)
  - Radio Research Lab, 1943-1945 (Box 57, Folder 24)
- Series XIII: Personal Interests, 1965-1966; 1972
  This series has two Subseries. The first is the Street Lighting for the Morningside addition, 1965-1966. This second contains reports, correspondence, meeting minutes, petitions, and specifications. The second series is the Tucson police helicopter surveillance, 1972. The bulk of this series is correspondence between Dr. Kuiper and the City of Tucson.
  - Subseries 1:Lighting - Morningside Addition District, Tucson
    - Final report on street lighting Morningside addition district, Tucson, Arizona, 1965-1966 (Box 57, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 57, Folder 26)
    - Meeting minutes, 1965-1966 (Box 57, Folder 27)
    - Petitions, [1965] (Box 57, Folder 28)
    - Specifications for Morningside addition district lighting improvements, 1966 (Box 57, Folder 29)
    - General, 1965-1966 (Box 57, Folder 30)
  - Subseries 2: Tucson police helicopter surveillance
    - Untitled (Box 58, Folder 1)
- Series XIV: Photographs, 1909-1973
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  - Air Masses for McDonald Observatory, undated (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Cerro Los Leones Chile Argentina border, December 1961 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Earth photographs, undated (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Hawaii Mauna Kea Summit aerial photographs, 1964 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Mars, 1907-1940’s (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Mauna Kea Dedication, July 20, 1964 (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Moon photographs, 1943 (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Moon photographs, [1960’s] (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Mount Lemon, 1970 (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - People Photographs, 1955-1973 (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Prints of Nebulae taken with the Curtis Schmidt Telescope, Cerro Tololo Inter-American Observatory, undated (Box 58, Folder 13)
  - Photographs taken at the Steward Observatory 90 inch telescope, [1970] (Box 58, Folder 14)
  - Planets, moon, etc., [1950] (Box 58, Folder 15)
  - Planets, moon, etc., [1909]; [1937] (Box 58, Folder 16)
  - Planets, moon, etc., [1909]; [1947] (Box 58, Folder 17)
  - Prints of Saturn, Mars and Jupiter by G.H. Herbig, 1909; 1917,; 1939,; 1948, (Box 58, Folder 18)
  - Ranger VII Team, 1964 (Box 58, Folder 19)
  - Satellites and Diagrams, 1949-1950 (Box 58, Folder 20)
  - Scenic Photographs – majority from Mount Locke, McDonald Observatory, 1935 (Box 58, Folder 21)
  - Scientific Photographs, undated (Box 58, Folder 22)
  - Smoke and steam sources in the Tucson basin, 1968 (Box 58, Folder 23)
  - Yerkes Observatory photographed with different filters, 1947 (Box 58, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 58, Folder 25)
- Series XV: Newspaper Clippings pertaining to Gerard Kuiper, 1942-1974
  This series is arranged by chronologically.
  - 1942-1974 (Box 58, Folder 26)
  - 1949-1973 (Box 58, Folder 27)
  - 1948-1974 (Box 58, Folder 28)
- Series XVI: Oversize, 1911-1968.
  This series contains oversized materials which would not fit into the main collection.
  - Photograph of Ranger Team for Newsweek, 1964 (Box 59, Item 1)
  - 20th Anniversary of the 1st Council of Physics. Photograph album, 1911-1967 (Box 59, Item 2)
  - Photographs of Smoke and steam sources in the Tucson Basin, undated (Box 59, Item 3)
  - Unknown photograph, undated (Box 59, Item 4)
  - Visual Measure of double stars, June 1929-March 1931 (Box 60, Item 1)
  - Photographs of Smoke and steam sources in the Tucson Basin, [1947] (Box 60, Item 2)
  - Visual stars, binary stars, double stars publications, 1923; 1928,; 1931,; 1937-1938 (Box 60, Item 3)
- Series XVII: Slides, 1948–1974.
  The slides date from March 1948 through October 1974. The majority of slides appears to be taken by Dr. Kuiper and are of a personal nature; they include pictures of his family, his gardens, his houses in Tucson and Chicago, visitors, trips, vacations. There are some work related slides including (but not limited to); lava, Mt Lemmon, Tomanoc Hill, Kitt Peak, Catalina Observatory, air pollution and smog, Hawaii, NASA, etc.
  - Subseries 1: These slides are organized by date into 28 metal slide containers. Each container has a subject guide which links the title to the appropriate numbered slide., March 1948 – March 1962.
    - March 1948 - July 1949. (Box 61, Item 1)
    - July 1949 - June 1950. (Box 61, Item 2)
    - June 1950 - April 1951. (Box 61, Item 3)
    - April - August 1951. (Box 61, Item 4)
    - [missing] (Box 61, Item 5)
    - [missing] (Box 61, Item 6)
    - September 1952 - April 1953 (Box 61, Item 7)
    - May – December 1953 (Box 61, Item 8)
    - January – April 1954 (Box 62, Item 9)
    - April – July 1954 (Box 62, Item 10)
    - July 1954 – April 1955 (Box 62, Item 11)
    - April – September 1955 (Box 62, Item 12)
    - September 1955 – May 1956 (Box 62, Item 13)
    - May – September 1956 (Box 62, Item 14)
    - September 1956 – May 1957 (Box 63, Item 15)
    - May – July 1957 (Box 63, Item 16)
    - July – October 1957 (Box 63, Item 17)
    - October – December 1957 (Box 63, Item 18)
    - March – July 1958 (Box 63, Item 19)
    - [missing] (Box 63, Item 20)
    - September 1958 – February 1959 (Box 63, Item 21)
    - [missing] (Box 64, Item 22)
    - March - September 1959 (Box 64, Item 23)
    - September 1959 –March 1960 (Box 64, Item 24)
    - April – November 1960 (Box 64, Item 25)
    - November 1960 – April 1961 (Box 64, Item 26)
    - April – July 1961 (Box 64, Item 27)
    - August 1961- March 1962 (Box 64, Item 28)
    - Spring 1962 – October 18, 1962 (Box 65, Item 29)
    - October 18 – December 25, 1962 (Box 65, Item 30)
    - Mostly documentation of progress on Catalina Observatory sites, December 1970 (Box 65, Item 31)
    - Majority are of a personal nature, in chronological order, 1951-1974 (Box 65, Item 32)
    - Hawaii trip, 1968 (Box 65, Item 33)
  - Subseries 2: The slides in this subseries are organized into yellow slide boxes. Slide boxes (folders) 1 through 263 are dated from 1952 to 1974. Slide boxes numbered 263 to 372 are undated. The majority of boxes do have labels. I have done my best to transcribe the labels., April 1965 – May 1973.
    - Family pictures, 1952 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - No label, 1952 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Trip Chicago-Boston and return by air for lecture at Lexington, MA, May 26, 1958 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Trip to Dayton, Summer 1958 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Paul’s graduation at Wayland, June 13-14, 1959 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Personal and scenic pictures, May-June, 1959 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - At home and garden, 1964 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Villa Jardin, Sarah to church Easter; April 17-18, 1965 (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Trip to China Lake, April 22, 1965 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Flagstaff (Pl data center), Tempe; Family at home;; May 1965 (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - Jet Propulsion Meeting (JPL), May 17, 1965 (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - Telescope (LA), May 19, 1965 (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - Mogollons Albuquerque, Grant’s lava fields; group photo;; May 19, 1965 (Box 66, Folder 13)
    - Mogollons, New Mexico, Catalina Station from air; May 25, 1965 (Box 66, Folder 14)
    - Arrival of 61” on Catalina Station Site 1, May 26, 1965 (Box 66, Folder 15)
    - Catalina’s, [1965] (Box 66, Folder 16)
    - At home, After planting; Arrival in London (Big Ben),; June 1-3, 1965 (Box 66, Folder 17)
    - London, Holland; June 4-5, 1965 (Box 66, Folder 18)
    - Family in Eindhoven, Netherlands, June 6, 1965 (Box 66, Folder 19)
    - Nijmegen, Netherlands, Serra; June 6, 1965 (Box 66, Folder 20)
    - Home, Lucy; June 18, 1965 (Box 66, Folder 21)
    - [missing] (Box 67, Folder 22)
    - McCartys lava flow, June 22, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 23)
    - Flight back to Grants, Zunni Lake; Springerville depression,; June 22-26, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 24)
    - End of trip to Grants, Socorro; Carrizozo flow;; La Mesa; June 22-26, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 25)
    - Carrizozo; New Mexico, June 26, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 26)
    - [missing] (Box 67, Folder 27-28)
    - La Mesa, Deming volcano's; June 26, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 29)
    - Sunset Crater, Meteor Crater; July 7, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 30)
    - Bonito flow, Flagstaff; July 7, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 31)
    - [missing] (Box 67, Folder 32)
    - Westinghouse visit to Catalina, Carrizozo flow; July 20, 26, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 33)
    - [missing] (Box 67, Folder 34)
    - Grants flow, moon; Zuni-Gallup regions;; Devils Canyon,; July 24, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 35)
    - [missing] (Box 67, Folder 36)
    - Morenci Mine, trip to Alpine; August 15, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 37)
    - White Mountains, Grants; St. Johns;; Zuni,; August 15, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 38)
    - [missing] (Box 67, Folder 39 and 40)
    - Lucy, trip to Cal Tech; Venus Slides; September 12-13, 16,1965 (Box 67, Folder 41)
    - Cal Tech Planetary Conference (Venus, Mars), September 16-17, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 42)
    - [missing] (Box 67, Folder 43)
    - Dedication of NASA Space Science building, garden views; October 22, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 44)
    - El Paso Craters, Franklin Mountains; Meeting on Voyager 7; October-November 1965 (Box 67, Folder 45)
    - Mt. Hopkins, [November 1965] (Box 67, Folder 46)
    - Kitt Peak National Observatory (KNPO), home (Paul) (Box 67, Folder 47)
    - Gemini Flight, Catalina Snow; December 19, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 48)
    - Snow on Catalina’s (1), December 19, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 49)
    - Snow on Catalina’s (2), December 19, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 50)
    - Rock slide on Catalina Highway, Lucy at fire; December 19, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 51)
    - Garden, December 19, 1965 (Box 68, Folder 52)
    - Sabino Canyon Floods, December 24, 1965 (Box 68, Folder 53)
    - Christmas dinner and days thereafter, December 25-30,1965 (Box 68, Folder 54)
    - Trip to Jet Propulsion Laboratory (Colorado River)to Burbank, January 8, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 55)
    - Catalina’s, San Miguel Mine collapses, January 14, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 56)
    - LPL visit by D. Holmes, New York wakes up to ice; Pembroke;; Capt. Mercer,; February 8-27, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 57)
    - Tumamoc Observatory; Dr. Hills visit to Space Science building, March 4-22, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 58)
    - Tulips and flowers at home, March 27-30, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 59)
    - Easter, April 5-12, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 60)
    - Garden, trip to Carrizozo NM lava fields; April 14, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 61)
    - Trip to Carrizozo NM lava fields, April 14, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 62)
    - Flowers at home, Space Science Building; San Xavier Mission,; April 18-25, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 63)
    - [missing] (Box 68, Folder 64-65)
    - Last of Carrizozo trip, May 4, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 66)
    - Ireland, London; Frankfurt;; Vienna,; May 9, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 67)
    - Vienna University, Schönbrunn Palace; May 12, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 68)
    - Zagreb streets and buildings, May 13, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 69)
    - Zagreb Falls, May 14, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 70)
    - Yugoslavia, Vienna; Holland arrival; May 14-19, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 71)
    - Eindhoven; Netherlands trip, Amsterdam departure; Greenland and glaciers,; May 21-22, 1965 (Box 68, Folder 72)
    - Trip to China Lake, Surveyor shadow on Moon; June 10, 1966; June 14, 1966; July 31, 1966; August 10, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 73)
    - Paul’s photographs for W. Wilde, visit to Appleton Farms; Paul on rocks,; July 31, 1966; August 10, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 74)
    - Tucson, Mt. Hualapai; Lake Mohave;; Colorado River;; Lake Mead;; Mt. Charleston, Nevada;; Oregon,; August 14, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 75)
    - Death Valley, Walker Lake, Nevada; Reno, Nevada;; Pyramid Lake, Oregon;; Diamond Carter;; Matthew Marshes;; Lake Harvey,; [August 14, 1966] (Box 69, Folder 76)
    - Oregon, Alkali flats near Lake Harney; Lake Pauline;; Newberry Carter; Lava Butte,; August 14-15, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 77)
    - Oregon, Lava Butts; pumice deposit;; volcanic bomb,; August 15, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 78)
    - Oregon, Fort Rock; lava tunnel;; forest fire smoke;; Mt. Jefferson,; August 15, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 79)
    - Oregon, Black Mt.; Horse Ridge garden;; Forest fire smoke pattern; Diamond Crater,; August 16, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 80)
    - Oregon, Diamond Crater; Alkali Flats; sand dunes; August 16, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 81)
    - [missing] (Box 69, Folder 82)
    - Oregon, Newberry Crater; August 16, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 83)
    - [missing] (Box 69, Folder 84)
    - Crater Lake, Shasta; Bay Area,; August 17, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 85)
    - Golden Gate and fog, Mount Diablo; San Joaquin Valley;; Kofa Mountains,; [August 17, 1966] (Box 69, Folder 86)
    - At home (front garden), Chiricahua trip; September 3-5, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 87)
    - Garden views, Shashi and friend; September 7-11, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 88)
    - Kitt Peak, Pine Crater; Baja, California;; Kitt Peak National Observatory(KPNO); September 21, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 89)
    - Baja California, September 21, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 90)
    - Baja California, September 21, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 91)
    - Baja California; return to Tucson via Yuma, September 21, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 92)
    - Garden, work starting on site 1; September 25-30, 1966; October 1-5, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 93)
    - Start construction of dormitory, stand by power system; path for walkway at site; October 20-25, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 94)
    - Site I construction, October 27, 1966; November 2, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 95)
    - Dormitory Site I, garden at home; November 3-6, 1966 (Box 70, Folder 96)
    - [missing] (Box 70, Folder 97-98)
    - Paul-Albuquerque, Kiepenheuer; pouring the walk at site I,; November 27-29, 1966 (Box 70, Folder 99)
    - Construction Catalina Observatory, December 3, 1966 (Box 70, Folder 100)
    - At home, Otto Heckmann visit; San Francisco,; December 4, 1966; December 9, 1966 (Box 70, Folder 101)
    - Garden, lodge; December 17, 1966 (Box 70, Folder 102)
    - Lunch at de Wiess, Mel and Cylde Doran building of water tank; starting road to lodge,; December 18, 1966; December 22, 1966 (Box 70, Folder 103)
    - Clean up at Site I, Nick visit – Mel takes us to Site I; start flight to Mt. Lemmon,; December 22, 1966,; January 1-2, 1967 (Box 70, Folder 104)